Guide to the Jackson J. Benson's The true adventures of John Steinbeck, writer: research materials, 1935-1980
Department of Special Collections
Benson, Jackson J. The true adventures of John Steinbeck, writer: research materials,
1935-1980
M0522
Benson, Jackson J.
9 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Research materials for Benson's biography of Steinbeck consisting of interviews, correspondence, articles, book reviews and other papers.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Jackson Benson, 1984-1986.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Research materials for Benson's biography of Steinbeck consisting of interviews, correspondence, articles, book reviews and other papers.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Benson, Jackson J.; Collins, Tom.; Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968.
Collection Contents
- Series 1. Research files
  - Articles by Steinbeck, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 1)
    Also includes parts of books, forewords, reprintings
  - Reviews of Steinbeck's books, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 2)
  - Magazine material about Steinbeck (Time, Newsweek, etc.), Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 3)
  - Reference work articles about Steinbeck (Who's Who, Encyclopedias, Twentieth Century Authors, etc.), Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 4)
  - Criticism of Steinbeck's works: journal articles and parts of books, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 4)
  - Criticism of Steinbeck's works: journal articles and parts of books, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 5)
  - Criticism of Steinbeck's works: journal articles and parts of books, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 6)
  - Steinbeck articles. In Figaro1954 Summer, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 6)
  - Letters to Alicia. Steinbeck articles. In Newsday1965, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 6)
  - Letters to Alicia. Steinbeck articles. In Newsday1965, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 7)
  - Childhood interviews, college interviews, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 7)
  - Tahoe interviews, first marriage interviews, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 8)
  - Second marriage interviews, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 9)
  - Third marriage interviews, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 9)
  - Third marriage interviews, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 10)
  - Childhood materials, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 10)
  - College materials, Tahoe materials, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 11)
  - First marriage materials, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 11)
  - First marriage materials, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 12)
  - Second marriage materials, third marriage materials, Accession no. 1984-096 (Box 12)
  - Elaine Steinbeck correspondence1971-1990, Accession no. 1998-006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Joel Hedgpeth correspondence1971-1984, Accession no. 1998-006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mrs. E.G. Beth Ainsworth correspondence1974-1981, nd, Accession no. 1998-006 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Carlton "Dook" Sheffield correspondence1970-1986, Accession no. 1998-006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Gwen Steinbeck correspondence1970-1971, Accession no. 1998-006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carol (Steinbeck) Brown1970-1974, Accession no. 1998-006 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Thom Steinbeck harrassment1980-1984, Accession no. 1998-006 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series 2. Audiovisual materials
  - Mr. and Mrs. Ernest Martin, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Mrs. Ben Valcani (Tony Jackson), Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Dr. Denton Cox, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Sol Liebner and Dr. Denton Cox, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Tom Ginzburg, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Willard Bascomb, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Terrence McNally, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Shirley Fisher, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Robert Wallsten, Accession no. 1984-096; 3 audiocassettes
  - Mrs. Margaret Gemmell Judah, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Burgess Meredith, Accession no. 1984-096; 3 audiocassettes
  - Dorothy Donahue, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Ellwood Graham, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Annie Laurie Williams, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Carlton Sheffield, Accession no. 1984-096; 3 audiocassettes
  - Elaine Steinbeck, Jean Boone (Elaine's sister), Thom Steinbeck, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Dean Storey, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Webster Street, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Rolf Bolin, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Mavis McIntosh, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Lewis Milestone, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Richard Albee, Accession no. 1984-096; 3 audiocassettes
  - Mrs. David Kinkaid and Lloyd Shebley, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Gwyn (Gwen) Steinbeck, Accession no. 1984-096; 4 audiocassettes
  - Glen Graves, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Lynn Loesser and Xenia Cage, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Lynn Loesser, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Lynn Loesser and Cornell Capa, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Nathaniel Benchley, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Mrs. Jerome Brody, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Charles L. McNichols, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Elia Kazan, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Allen Ludden, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Roger Condon, Delbert West, William Welt, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Robert Cathcart, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Delbert West, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 reels
  - Barnaby Conrad, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Robert Sears, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Jerry Gilmer, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Peter Bridges, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Sam Gipson, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Norman Cousins, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Phil Strong, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Polly Teas, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - John Kenneth Galbraith, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Abe Burrows, Budd Schulberg, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - (Nobel Prize Ceremony -- Swedish Television audiotape), Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Budd Schulberg, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Frank Lloyd, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - John Hersey, Benchley papers, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Frank Kilkenny, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Joseph Bryan III, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Edward Albee, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - William L. Shirer, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Mr. and Mrs. Harold E. Ebright, Jr., Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Mrs. Virginia Welhelmson, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - James Harkins, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Notes from Elaine, Xenia Cage, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Gordon Manning, Jack Watson, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Francis Whittaker, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Dr. Horace Jones, Helen Hosmer, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Helen Hosmer, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Jack Calvin, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Jack Calvin, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Burl Ives, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Mrs. Nunnally Johnson, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Sandy Oliver, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Douglas Fairbanks, Jr., Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Catherine Hill, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Virginia Scardgill, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Mrs. Stanley Heuit (Gwyn's mother), Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - John O'Reilly, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Tex Travis, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Jules Buck, Accession no. 1984-096; 2 audiocassettes
  - Arthur Miller, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Ella Winter, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - John Fearnley, Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - (Sag Harbor -- impressions of house and environment), Accession no. 1984-096; 1 audiocassette
  - Elaine Steinbeck (Series #1, 3 tapes; Series #2, 16 tapes; Series #3, 2 tapes), Accession no. 1984-096; 20 audiocassettes
  - The Young John Steinbeck: cassette tape set 1975, Accession no. 1998-006; 2 audiotapes (Box 1, Folder 1)